Inventaris van het archief van de Stichting World Press Photo, 1955 - 2009
Nationaal Archief, Den Haag
- PUBLICATIEARCHIEF, A.
  - Masterclass publicaties., 1994-2009; 202-218; 17 delen
    - Joop Swart Masterclass ‘98 - Food, 1998, 206
      English. Exhibitions: Netherlands Institute for Photography, Rotterdam, 11-29 November 1998 en Melkweg Gallery, Amsterdam, 21 February – 14 March 1999. Publisher: Special edition by VNU tijdschriften. Editor: Kari Lundelin. Design: Hans van Blommestein. ISSN -. Size: 24 pp., 34x25 cm.
    - Joop Swart Masterclass ‘99 - Power, 1999, 207
      English. Exhibitions: Netherlands Institute for Photography, Rotterdam, 10-21 November 1999 en Melkweg Gallery, Amsterdam, 12 April – 7 May 2000. Publisher: Special edition by VNU tijdschriften. Editor: Kari Lundelin. Design: Hans van Blommestein. ISSN -. Size: 24 pp., 34x25 cm.
    - Joop Swart Masterclass 2000 - Work, 2000, 208
      English. Exhibition: Netherlands Institute for Photography, Rotterdam, 8 - 16 November 2000. Editors: Terri J. Kester, Kari Lundelin. Design: Heijdens Karwei, Amsterdam. ISSN -. Size: 40 pp., 17x25 cm.
    - Joop Swart Masterclass 2001 - ID/Identity, 2001, 209
      English. Exhibition: Nederlands Foto Instituut, Rotterdam, 7 - 28 November 2001.Editors: Terri J. Kester, Kari Lundelin. Design: Heijdens Karwei, Amsterdam. ISSN 1568-6809. Size: 40 pp., 17x25 cm.
    - Joop Swart Masterclass 2002 - Faith, 2002, 210
      English. Exhibition: FOAM, Amsterdam, 13 Nov. – 12 January 2003. Editors: Terri J. Kester, Kari Lundelin. Design: Heijdens Karwei, Amsterdam. ISSN 1568-6809. Size: 40 pp., 17x25 cm.
    - Enough - Joop Swart Masterclass 2003, 2003, 211
      English. Exhibition: Foam Photography Museum, Amsterdam, 7 Nov. 2003 – 11 Jan. 2004. Editor: Terri J. Kester. Design: Heijdens Karwei, Amsterdam. ISSN 1568-6809. Size: 64 pp., 16x23,8 cm.
    - Joop Swart Masterclass – the first decade, 2004, 212
      English. Exhibition: Compilation of all previous themes by Erik Kessels. Publisher: (c) 2004 Stichting World Press Photo, Amsterdam; Gijs Stork, Artimo, Amsterdam. Text edit and captions: Terri J. Kester. Design: Erik Kessels, KesselsKramer, Amsterdam. ISSN 90-803698-2-9. Size: ? pp., 30x23 cm.
    - Joop Swart Masterclass 2004 - Pride, 2004, 213
      English. Exhibition: Foam_Photography Museum, Amsterdam, 12 Nov. 2004 – 2 Jan. 2005. Publisher: (c) 2004 Stichting World Press Photo, Amsterdam. Text editor: Lucy Crystal. Design: Heijdens Karwei, Amsterdam. ISSN 1568-6809. Size: 64 pp., 16x23,8 cm.
    - Joop Swart Masterclass 2005 - Ordinary, 2005, 214
      English. Exhibition: Arti et Amicitiae, Amsterdam, 11 Nov. – 30 December 2005. Publisher: (c) 2005 Stichting World Press Photo, Amsterdam. Text editor: Lucy Crystal. Design: Heijdens Karwei, Amsterdam. ISSN 1568-6809. Size: 64 pp., 16x23,8 cm.
    - Joop Swart Masterclass 2006 - Risk, 2006, 215
      English. Exhibition: Foam_ Fotografiemuseum, Amsterdam, 10 Nov. 2006 – 7 Jan. 2007. Publisher: (c) 2006 Stichting World Press Photo, Amsterdam. Text editor: Rodney Bolt. Design: Heijdens Karwei, Amsterdam. ISSN 1568-6809. Size: ? pp., 16x23,8 cm.
    - Joop Swart Masterclass 2007 - Fragile, 2007, 216
      English. Book launch at Foam_ Fotografiemuseum, Amsterdam, 8 Nov. 2007. Publisher: (c) 2007 Stichting World Press Photo, Amsterdam. Text editor: Rodney Bolt. Design: Heijdens Karwei, Amsterdam. ISSN 978-90-803698-3-2. Size: ? pp., 22,5x17 cm.
    - Joop Swart Masterclass 2007 - Balance, 2008, 217
      English. Book launch at Foam_ Fotografiemuseum, Amsterdam, 13 Nov. 2008. Publisher: (c) 2008 Stichting World Press Photo, Amsterdam. Text editor: Rodney Bolt. Design: Heijdens Karwei, Amsterdam. ISSN 978-90-803698-5-6. Size: ? pp., 22,5x17 cm.
    - Joop Swart Masterclass 2007 - Touch -, 2009, 218
      English. Book launch at Foam_ Fotografiemuseum, Amsterdam, 5 Nov. 2009. Publisher: (c) 2009 Stichting World Press Photo, Amsterdam. Text editor: Rodney Bolt. Design: Heijdens Karwei, Amsterdam. ISSN 978-90-803698-6-3. Size: ? pp., 22,5x17 cm.
  - Workshop publicaties., 1999-2008; 219-229; 11 delen
    - East Africa Photography Workshop, 1999, 219
      Workshop: East Africa Photography Workshop, [Nairobi, Kenia, September 1999]. Publisher: (c) 1999 Stichting World Press Photo, Amsterdam. Design: Heijdens Karwei. ISBN -. Size: ? pp., 22x21,2 cm.
    - Pleasure of Life, 2001, 220
      Workshop: Development of Photojournalism in Developing Countries 1. 1998-2000. Publisher: (c) 2001 Stichting World Press Photo; KIT Publishers, Royal Tropical Institute, Amsterdam. Editors: Terri J. Kester, Kari Lundelin. Design: Heijdens Karwei. ISBN 90-6832-509-4. Size: ? pp., Box 24x21 cm.
    - Production, 2002, 221
      Workshop: South East Asian Photography Workshop 2002. Publisher: (c) 2002 Stichting World Press Photo, Amsterdam. Text: Terri J. Kester. Design: Heijdens Karwei. ISBN -. Size: 94 pp., 22x12 cm.
    - Young People At Risk, 2002, 222
      Workshop: Young People At Risk [Baltic’s Workshop] 2001-2002. Publisher: (c) 2002 Stichting World Press Photo, Amsterdam. Co-production with the European Cultural Foundation. Editing: Terri J. Kester. Design: Heijdens Karwei. ISBN -. Size: 70+26 pp., 23x17 cm.
    - Inside/ Outsight - Gender and Environment, 2004, 223
      Workshop: Development of Photojournalism in Developing Countries 2. 2001-2003. Publisher: (c) 2004 Stichting World Press Photo, Amsterdam. Editor: Robert Pledge. Design: Koeweiden Postma. ISBN -. Size: 2 books 132 each pp., 25x20 cm.
    - Inside/ Outsight, 224
      Workshop: Information in Dutch for visitors of the traveling open-air-exhibition. Publisher: (c) 2004 Stichting World Press Photo, Amsterdam. Editor: Maarten Koets, Claudia Hinterseer (WPPh). Design: Koeweiden Postma. ISBN -. Size: 8 pp., 42x29,7 cm.
    - Migrations, 2004, 225
      Workshop: Asia-Europe Forum for Young Photographers 2003. Publisher: (c) 2004 Stichting World Press Photo, Amsterdam. Editing: Rodney Bolt. Design: Heijdens Karwei. ISBN -. Size: ? pp., 11x17 cm.
    - Urban Environment, 2005, 226
      Workshop: Asia-Europe Forum for Young Photographers 2004. Publisher: (c) 2005 Asia-Europe Foundation, Singapore. Co-production with World Press Photo and the Vietnam Ministry of Culture and Information. Text editor: Rodney Bolt. Design: Publishing Interface Pte Ltd, Singapore in collaboration with Heijdens Karwei. ISBN -. Size: ? pp., A4 cm.
    - Effective training techniques - A manual for the local tutor, 2006, 227
      Workshop: Training of Trainers 2006. Publisher: (c) 2006 Michael Harrison. Published under the auspices of Stichting World Press Photo, Amsterdam. Design: Heijdens Karwei. ISBN -. Size: 64 pp., 21x14,9 cm.
    - Partnerships in Developing Photojournalism, 2007, 228
      Workshop: Development of Photojournalism in Developing Countries 3. [Part 1] Tanzania, Indonesia, Nigeria, Armenia. 2004-2008. Publisher: (c) 2007 Stichting World Press Photo, Amsterdam. Text editing: Ronnie Godeanu. Design: Heijdens Karwei. ISBN -. Size: 480 pp., 14x19,4 cm.
    - World Press Photo: New Stories, 2008, 229
      Workshop: [No workshop] 10 former participants in World Press Photo training programs and workshops in developing countries throw new light on the United Nations’ Millennium Development Goals. Publisher: (c) 2008 Stichting World Press Photo, Amsterdam. Text by Rodney Bolt, with an introduction by Adrian Evans. Design: Heijdens Karwei. ISBN 978-90-803698-4-9. Size: 256 pp., 31½x24 cm.
  - Nieuwsbrieven., 1974-2009; 230-237; 8 omslagen
    In het Engels. A4-formaat.
    - Newsletter, 1974, 230
      In het Nederlands.
    - Newsletter, 1988-11, 231
    - Newsletter, 1989-12, 232
    - Newsletter, 1990-03, 233
    - Newsletter, 1990-07 - 1996-06, 234
    - Newsletter, 1996-12 - 1999-12, 235
    - Newsletter, 2000-06 - 2004-12, 236
    - Review, 2005-07 - 2009-06, 237
  - Corporate publicaties van de Stichting World Press Photo., 1976-2007; 238-242; 5 omslagen
    - Stichting World Press Photo Holland - een naam in de fotografische wereld an image in the world of photography, 1976, 238
      Dutch + English. Publisher: (c) Stichting World Press Photo Holland. Size: 6 pp., A4 folder.
    - World Press Photo - Contest and exhibition of the press photos of the year. An international event. Wedstrijd en tentoonstelling van de persfoto’s van het jaar. Een internationale manifestatie, 1984, 239
      English+ Dutch. Publisher: (c) World Press Photo Holland Foundation. Size: 6 pp., A4 folder.
    - World Press Photo - Wettstreit und Austellung der Pressefotos des Jahres. Eine internationale Veranstaltung. Le concours et l’exposition des photos de la presse de l’année. Une manifestation internationale, 1984, 239
      German+ French. Publisher: (c) World Press Photo Holland Foundation. Size: 6 pp., A4 folder.
    - World Press Photo - Profile of International Photojournalism, 1988, 240
      English. Publisher: (c) World Press Photo Holland Foundation. Text: Dick Schaap, Hanny van den Horst. Design: Hans van Blommestein, Christine Simonis. Size: 16 pp., 21x14,9 cm.
    - World Press Photo - Überblick des Internationalen Fotojournalismus, 1988, 240
      German. Publisher: (c) World Press Photo Holland Foundation. Text: Dick Schaap, Hanny van den Horst. Design: Hans van Blommestein, Christine Simonis. Size: 16 pp., 21x14,9 cm.
    - World Press Photo - [in Russian], 1988, 240
      Russian. Publisher: (c) World Press Photo Holland Foundation. Text: Dick Schaap, Hanny van den Horst. Design: Hans van Blommestein, Christine Simonis. Size: 16 pp., 21x14,9 cm.
    - World Press Photo - Standing up for Photography, 1994, 241
      English. Publisher: (c) World Press Photo Foundation. Text: Maggie Laszlo, Kari Lundelin. Design: Teun van der Heijden. Photography: Bart Nieuwenhuijs. Size: 16 pp., 24,5x24,5 cm.
    - World Press Photo, 2005, 242
      English. Publisher: (c) World Press Photo, 2005. Text editor: Rodney Bolt. Design: Heijdens Karwei. Size: 16 pp., 28x21 cm.
    - World Press Photo, 2007, 242
      English. Publisher: (c) World Press Photo, 2007. Text editor: Rodney Bolt. Design: Heijdens Karwei. Size: 16 pp., 28x21 cm.
  - Tentoonstellingspublicaties., 1956-2009; 243-267; 22 omslagen
    - World Press-Photo 55 - catalogus, 1955, 243
      Dutch. Publisher: NVF Nederlandse Vereniging van Fotojournalisten (Dutch Society of Photojournalists). Insert in ‘De Fotojournalist’, jubilee issue 1955; including list of all entries. Size: A4 fotokopie cm.
    - World Press Photo '56. Georganiseerd door de Nederlandse Vereniging van Fotojournalisten, 1956, 244
      Dutch. Publisher: NVF Nederlandse Vereniging van Fotojournalisten (Dutch Society of Photojournalists). Including list of all entries. Size: 24 pp., 26,7x19,8 cm.
    - world press photo 57, 1957, 245
      Dutch. Publisher: NVF Nederlandse Vereniging van Fotojournalisten (Dutch Society of Photojournalists). Including list of all entries. Size: A4 fotokopie cm.
    - World Press Photo 59, 1959, 246
      Dutch + English summary. Publisher: ‘´s-Gravenhage’, monthly magazine for the municipality of The Hague. Including list of all entries. Insert: Prijzen “World Press Photo 1959”. Size: 25,3x18,3 cm.
    - World Press Photo 61 - Haags Gemeentemuseum 4 Oktober t.m. 5 November 1961, 1961, 247
      Dutch + English+ French + German. Publisher: World Press Photo -The Hague- Holland Foundation. Including list of all entries. Insert: list of 1961 prize winners. Size: 2 publicaties van 38 en 4 pp., 25,5x18,4 cm.
    - World Press Photo ’62 - Haags Gemeentemuseum 28 November t/m 6 Januari 1963, 1962, 248
      Dutch + English+ French + German + Spanish. Publisher: World Press Photo -The Hague- Holland Foundation. Haags Gemeentemuseum. Including list of 1962 participants and list of all entries. Insert: list of 1962 prize winners. Size: 3 publicaties van 40, 16 en 4 pp., 25,7x18,3 cm.
    - World Press Photo 63, 1963, 249
      Dutch + English. Publisher: World Press Photo -The Hague- Holland Foundation (onleesbaar). Including list of all entries. Insert: list of 1963 prize winners. Size: 50+6 pp., A4 fotokopieën cm. Originelen in het Haags Gemeentearchief.
    - World Press Photo ’64 / The Hague, Holland. Concours annuel des meilleures photographies de presse du monde, 1964, 250
      Dutch + English+ French + German. Publisher: World Press Photo -The Hague- Holland. Including list of all entries. Size: 28 pp., 26,5x19 cm.
    - World Press Photo 10 / Jubileumkrant aangeboden door de Haagse dagbladen., 1965, 251
      Dutch + English+ French + German + Spanish. Publisher: Aangeboden door: Het Binnenhof, Haagse Courant, Het Vaderland. 10th anniversary newspaper. Including list of all entries (fotokopie). Size: 10 pp., 60x45 approx. cm.
    - World Press Photo 1966, 1966, 265
      Dutch + English. Publisher: Deze lijst van deelnemers wordt u aangeboden door Kodak. Newspaper, including list of all entries, sponsored by Kodak. Size: 20 pp., 44,5x30 cm.
    - World Press Photo 1967, 1967, 266
      Dutch + English. Publisher: Newspaper, including list of all entries, probably sponsored by Kodak. Size: 20 pp., 44,5x30 cm.
    - World Press Photo 1968-‘69, 1968-‘69, 267
      Dutch. Publisher: Newspaper, including list of all entries. Size: 20 pp., 44,5x30 cm.
    - World Press Photo 1971-72 / Catalogus – catalogue, 1971-‘72, 255
      Dutch + English. Publisher: World Press Photo Holland Foundation. Size: 20 pp., 26x21 cm.
    - World Press Photo 73 / 4 april t/m 13 mei Amsterdam-C, 1973, 256
      Dutch + English. Publisher: World Press Photo Holland Foundation. Size: 5 pp., folder 24,4x15,8 cm.
    - World Press Photo '91, 1991, ProPassportNEWS / Special World Press 91, 1991; ProPassportNEWS / Special World Press 92, 1992; ProPassportNEWS / Special World Press 93, 1993; 257
      English, Polish, French. Publisher: Eye Publishing Ltd., Warsaw. Kodak Professional Network. Size: 4 folders à 4 pp., A4 cm.
    - WORLD PRESS 1994 / photo witness, 1994, 258
      English, French, German, Italian, Spanish. Publisher: Pro Passport - Presented by Kodak Professional Imaging. Size: 5 folders à 6 pp., A4 cm.
    - WORLD PRESS 1995 / A picture, an echo, a conscience …, 1995, 259
      English, German, Italian. Publisher: Pro Passport - Presented by Kodak Professional Imaging. Size: 3 folders à 6 pp., A4 cm.
    - 1996 World Press Photo exhibition, 1996, 1997 World Press Photo exhibition, 1997; 260
      English, French, German, Italian, Spanish.With support from Eastman Kodak Company. Size: 6 folders à 6 pp., A4 cm.
    - World Press Photo 1998 / Visual thinking / How to become involved in a unique exhibition programme / Fact sheets / The Retrospective Exhibition, 1998, 261
      English A tribute to the skills of the photographer. Size: 6 folders à 4 en 2 pp., 63x50 en A4 cm.
    - World Press Photo / EXHIBITION 1999, 2000, 2001en 2002, 1999-2002, 262
      English. Size: 4 folders à 6 pp., A4 cm.
    - World Press Photo 03, 04, 05, 06, 07, 08 en 09, 2003-2009, 263
      English. Also corporate brochure. Size: 7 folders à 16 en 4 pp., 21,5x15,5 en 15x21 cm.
    - Tentoonstellingsaffiches 1955, 1973, 1975 t/m 2009 en 2003 Kinderjury, 1955-2009, 264; 43 affiches
      - 1955 Photo: Eric Parbst, Denmark., -
        Amsterdam. Size: 70,3 x 39,7 cm.(Print from scan. Original poster owned by Ian Denning).
      - 1973 Photo: Vincent Mentzel, the Netherlands., -
        Amsterdam. Size: 60 x 40 cm.
      - 1975 Photo: Boudewijn Neuteboom (the Netherlands). Design: Henk Maas., -
        Amsterdam. Size: 60,0 x 40,0 cm. In duplo.
      - 1976 Photo: 1st prize Happy News by David Valentine, Daily News, South Africa., -
        Amsterdam. Size: 61,4 x 40,0 cm. In duplo.
      - 1977 Photo: Ernest Schworck (UPI) – USA – first prize Sports., -
        No imprint. Size: 65,8 x 40,1 cm.
      - 1978 Photo: Sven-Erik Sjöberg, Dagens Nyheter, Sweden., -
        Emmeloord. Size: 65,5 x 40 cm.
      - 1979 Photo: Hans Rauchensteiner, Sven Simon Agency, BRD., -
        No imprint. Size: 65,5 x 40 cm.
      - 1980 Photo: Hilmar Pabel, BRD., -
        Amsterdam. Size: 59,5 x 40,0 cm.
      - 1981 Photo: René Lévêque, France., -
        No imprint. Size: 66,0 x 40,0 cm.
      - 1982 Photo: World Press Photo of the Year 1981 (detail) by Manuel Pérez Barriopedro, Spain., -
      - 1983 Photo: Chuck Fishman (USA)., -
        Amsterdam. Size: 66,5 x 40,0 cm. In duplo.
      - 1984 Photo: Manoocher (France/Iran), Sipa-press. Design: Hans van Blommestein, Louis Voogt., -
        No imprint. Size: 66,7 x 39,9 cm.
      - 1985 Photo: José Azel, Contact Press Images (Cuba). Design: Hans van Blommestein, Louis Voogt., -
        Amsterdam. Size: 66,5 x 44,0 cm.
      - 1986 Photo: David B. Parker (USA). Design: Hans van Blommestein, Louis Voogt., -
        No imprint. Size: 66,5 x 40,0 cm.
      - 1987 Photo: Suresh Karadia, The Sunday Times (UK). Design: Hans van Blommestein, Louis Voogt., -
        Amsterdam. Size: 65,7 x 39,6 cm. In duplo.
      - 1988 Photo: J.B. Diederich, Contact Press Images, USA. Design: Hans van Blommestein, Louis Voogt., -
        Amsterdam. Size: 57,8 x 39,7 cm.
      - 1989-a Photo: Allan Tannenbaum, Sygma, USA. Design: Hans van Blommestein, Louis Voogt., -
        Amsterdam. Size: 57,7 x 39,7 cm.
      - 1989-b Photo: Charles Hires (USA), Gamma., -
        No imprint. Size: 67,9 x 39,6 cm.
      - 1990 Photo: World Press Photo of the Year 1989 by Charlie Cole, Newsweek Mag., USA. Design: Hans van Blommestein, Louis Voogt., -
        Amsterdam. Size: 58,0 x 39,6 cm.
      - 1991 Photo: Hans Gedda, Sweden, Sygma, France. Design: Hans van Blommestein, Louis Voogt., -
        Amsterdam. Size: 63,1 x 39,6 cm.
      - 1992 Photo: Stéphane Compoint, Sygma, France. Design: Hans van Blommestein, Louis Voogt., -
        No imprint. Size: 70,1 x 39,5 cm.
      - 1993 Photo: Chris Steele-Perkins, Magnum Photos, UK. Design: Hans van Blommestein, Louis Voogt., -
      - 1994 Photo: Antoine Gyori, Sygma, France. Design: Hans van Blommestein, Louis Voogt., -
        Amsterdam. Size: 70,0 x 39,5 cm.
      - 1995 Photo: Keith Bernstein, UK, FSP/Gamma. Design: Hans van Blommestein, Louis Voogt., -
        No imprint. Size: 70,0 x 39,5 cm.
      - 1996 Photo: Luc Delahaye, France, Magnum for Newsweek. Design: Hans van Blommestein, Louis Voogt., -
        Amsterdam. Size: 70,1 x 39,6 cm.
      - 1997 Photo: Eric Bouvet, France, for VSD Magazine. Design: Hans van Blommestein, Louis Voogt., -
      - 1998 Photo: World Press Photo of the Year 1997 (detail) by Hocine, Algeria, Agence France-Presse. Designs: Heijdens Karwei., -
      - 1999 Photo: World Press Photo of the Year 1998 (detail) by Dayna Smith, USA, The Washinton Post. Design: Heijdens Karwei., -
      - 2000 Photo: World Press Photo of the Year 1999 (detail) by Claus Bjorn Larsen, Denmark, Berlingske Tidende. Design: Heijdens Karwei., -
      - 2001 Photo: World Press Photo of the Year 2000 (detail) by Lara Jo Regan, USA. Design: Heijdens Karwei., -
      - 2002 Photo: World Press Photo of the Year 2001 by Erik Refner, Denmark. Design: Heijdens Karwei., -
      - 2003 Photo: World Press Photo of the Year 2002 by Eric Grigorian, Armenia/USA. Design: Heijdens Karwei., -
        Amsterdam. Size: 59,4 x 42,0 cm.
      - 2004 Photo: World Press Photo of the Year 2003 by Jean-Marc Boujou, France, The Associated Press. Design: Heijdens Karwei., -
      - 2005 Photo: World Press Photo of the Year 2004 by Arko Datta, India, Reuters. Design: Heijdens Karwei., -
      - 2006 Photo: World Press Photo of the Year 2005 by Finbarr O’Reilly, Canada, Reuters. Design: Heijdens Karwei., -
        No imprint. Size: 59,4 x 42,0 cm.
      - 2007 Photo: World Press Photo of the Year 2006 by Spencer Platt, USA, Getty Images. Design: Heijdens Karwei., -
      - 2008 Photo: World Press Photo of the Year 2007 by Tim Hetherington, UK, for Vanity Fair. Design: Heijdens Karwei., -
      - 2009 Photo: World Press Photo of the Year 2008 by Anthony Suau, USA, for Time. Design: Heijdens Karwei., -
      - 2003 Exhibition 20 Years Children’s Award. Photo: Children’s Award 1993 by Joel Robine, France, Agence France-Presse. Design: Heijdens Karwei., -
        Amsterdam. Size: 59,5 x 42 cm.
  - Winnaarspublicaties., 1995-2001; 268-273; 5 delen
    - 1995 James Nachtwey 1990-1995 / The Inferno, 1995, 268
      English. Occasion: Winner of the World Press Photo of the Year 1994 award. Winners exhibition in the Nieuwe Kerk, Amsterdam 26 April – 4 June 1995. Publisher: (c) World Press Photo. Published in cooperation with Magazine Makers. Design: Teun van der Heijden. Size: 20 pp., 68x48 cm.
    - 1996 Lucian Perkins /The Washington Post, 1996, 269
      English. Occasion: Winner of the World Press Photo of the Year 1995 award. Winners exhibition in the Nieuwe Kerk, Amsterdam 26 April – 9 June 1996. Publisher: (c) World Press Photo. Design: David Griffin. Size: 20 pp., 68x48 cm.
    - 1997 Francesco Zizola / Six stories of children, 1997, 271
      English. Occasion: Winner of the World Press Photo of the Year 1996 award. Exhibition in the Nieuwe Kerk, Amsterdam 29 April – 14 June 1997. Publisher: MPI Books, Amstelveen. (c) 1997 Francesco Zizola/ Contrasto. Size: 6+4 pp., 2 sheets 59,5x83 cm in A4 double folded cover.
    - 1998 Hocine / Algeria, Somalia, 1998, 272
      English. Occasion: Winner of the World Press Photo of the Year 1997 award. Exhibition in the Nieuwe Kerk, Amsterdam 21 April – 1 June 1998. Publisher: MpiBooks, Amstelveen. (c) 1998 Hocine/ Agence France-Presse. Size: 6+4 pp., 2 sheets 59,5x84 cm in A4 double folded cover.
    - 2001 Lara Jo Regan / Photography makes the world go round, 2001, 273
      English. Occasion: Winner of the World Press Photo of the Year 2000 award. Exhibition in the Oude Kerk, Amsterdam 24 April – 4 June 2001. Publisher: Heijdens Karwei, Amsterdam. (c) Lara Jo Regan. Size: 16 pp., 21x15 cm.
  - Wedstrijd - Entry forms., 1956-2009; 274-277; 4 omslagen
    - 1956 - 1986, 274
    - 1987 - 1994, 275
    - 1995 - 2001, 276
    - 2002 - 2009, 277
  - Annual Reports / Jaarverslagen over de jaren 1995-2000., 1996-2001; 278; 1 omslag
  - Bijzondere boeken., 1983-2009; 279-286; 7 delen
    - World Press Photo ‘83, 1983, 279
      Spanish. Imprint: L’Obra Cultural de la Caja de Pensiones presenta la exposición World Press Photo ’83: En las ciudades de Barcelona, Madrid, Granollers, Lérida, Gerona y Tarragona. Septiembre 1983 - Febrero 1984. Publisher: Technipress S.A. de Ediciones, Madrid. ISBN 84-300-9780-5 Depósito Legal: M-27097-1983. Size: 112 pp., A4 - paperback
    - Eyewitness - World Press Photo ‘87, 1987, 280
      English. Signed Alon Reininger. Publisher: Elsevier Boeken BV, Amsterdam, Brussel. ISBN -. Size: 128 pp., A4 – paperback
    - Eyewitness - World Press Photo 1988, 1988, 281
      English. Imprint: Kodak, KLM. Publisher: Agon BV, Amsterdam. ISBN -. Size: 128 pp., A4 – paperback
    - Eyewitness - World Press Photo 1989/1990, 1989-1990, 282
      German. Doppelband. Publisher: Agon BV, Amsterdam. ISBN -. Size: 2x128 pp., A4 – paperback
    - World Press Photo Eyewitness 1993, 1993, 284
      English. Imprint: Asahi Shimbun. Publisher: Thames & Hudson, London, New York. ISBN 0-500-97408-X. Size: 132 pp., A4 – paperback
    - World Press Photo - Yearbook 1994, 1994, 285
      English. Signed Larry Towell. Publisher: Thames & Hudson, London, New York. ISBN 0-500-97412-8. Size: 132 pp., A4 – paperback
    - World Press Photo 09, 2009, 286
      Dutch. Signed Anthony Suau. Publisher: Mets & Schilt Uitgevers, Amsterdam. Lannoo Uitgeverij, Tielt, Belgium. Design: Heijdens Karwei. ISBN 978-94-900-4801-3; NUR 653. Size: 160 pp., 29,7 x 23 cm - paperback
  - Portfolio Foto CD's., 1995-1997; 297-299; 3 compactdiscs
    - World Press Photo Portfolio CD 1995, 1995, 297